Guide to the Kulchur Foundation records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Kulchur Foundation records,
1936-1994
[Bulk Dates: 1969-1989].
Kulchur Foundation.
29.74 linear ft. (50 document boxes, 1 half-size document box, 2 record storage cartons, 6 oversized flat boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#0732
4078552
Kulchur-- a little magazine focused on cultural criticism and later a small press, was an important publisher of avant-garde poets, particularly poets associated with what became known as the New York School. The Kulchur Foundation Records include administrative, financial and editorial records related to Kulchur Magazine, Kulchur Press, and the Kulchur Foundation. Additionally, it includes photographs, correspondence, artwork and manuscripts related to the Foundation or to its president-- writer, publisher, and art collector, Lita Hornick.
Historical Note
Publishing critical essays, commentary, reviews and original artwork by writers and artists such as Ted Berrigan, Alice Notley, and LeRoi Jones, Kulchur was an important vehicle for promoting American poets and cultural critics associated with the New American Poetry of the mid to late twentieth century, particularly the New York School of poets and artists.
The Kulchur Foundation, a non-profit publishing and arts organization, began as a small, literary journal in 1961. The magazine was founded by Marc Schleifer who also edited Kulchur 1 and Kulchur 2 before handing over administrative and editorial control of the magazine to Lita Hornick.
Lita Hornick, who was to become the driving force behind the magazine and Kulchr's subsequent publishing and arts patronage activities, was born Lita Rothbard in 1927 in Newark, New Jersey. She graduated from Barnard College in 1948, where she developed her taste for modern literature and avant-garde poetry. She went on to do graduate work in English at Columbia University, writing her masters thesis on feminist novelist Dorothy Richardson, and, later, her doctoral dissertation on the work of Dylan Thomas. She was married to Morton Hornick and had two sons.
When Hornick took the reigns of the magazine's third issue in 1961 she made significant changes to the publication. The first two issues of the magazine had been managed by Marc Schleifer and published annually--under Hornick's direction the magazine focused more on arts criticism and commentary rather than literary publication and increased its publication schedule to quarterly. Hornick also established Kulchur Press, Inc. as an incorporated business in 1961 (albeit one that never turned a profit and was almost entirely privately funded by her and her husband).
Though Ms. Hornick took over the administrative reigns of the magazine in 1961 with Kulchur 3, she assigned guest editors for the first few issues of the magazine that she published (Gilbert Sorrentino edited Kulchur 5, and Joel Oppenheimer guest-edited Kulchur 6). Starting with Kulchur 7, the magazine was run by Ms. Hornick as managing editor, but supported by an editorial board of LeRoi Jones, Gilbert Sorrentino, Frank O'Hara, Joseph LeSeur, and Bill Berskon. This general arrangement lasted for five issues before Hornick took over the sole editorship of the magazine starting with Kulchur 7 and lasting through the magazine's final issue, Kulchur 20.
The stress and hectic schedule of editing and publishing a quarterly wore on Hornick, so in 1966 she decided to alter the focus of Kulchur, Inc. away from periodicals and cultural commentary and towards publishing books, primarily of poetry. The first book published by Kulchur Press was the contemporary poetry anthology Poems Now, edited by Hettie Jones, though most subsequent books would veer away from the anthology format. Over the course of the Press's run, it published books by notable New York School poets such as Ted Berrigan, John Giorno, and Rochelle Owens, among a host of others. By far the venture's most successful book was Screen Tests, a book of poetry by Gerard Malanga accompanied by photographs of individuals taken by Andy Warhol. Hornick, an avid art collector, was very interested in these collaborations between visual artists and poets, and published a number of such volumes.
In 1970 the name of the organization officially changes from Kulchur Press to Kulchur Foundation to reflect its work as an arts funder and grant-giving agency as well as a publishing venture. This move also allowed the organization to obtain the tax exempt status available to it as a cultural foundation rather than a business. Though Kulchur's publishing efforts remained unchanged with this shift to foundation status, the foundation started to take on more cultural programming than it had previously, such as producing a series of poetry readings at the Museum of Modern Art starting in 1973 and co-producing theatrical productions. In 1981 Kulchur stopped publishing, though Hornick maintained foundation work in the name of Kulchur until her death in 2000.
Scope and Content
Kulchur-- a little magazine focused on cultural criticism and later a small press, was an important publisher of avant-garde poets, particularly poets associated with what became known as the New York School. The Kulchur Foundation Records include administrative, financial and editorial records related to Kulchur Magazine, Kulchur Press, and the Kulchur Foundation. Additionally, it includes photographs, correspondence, artwork and manuscripts related to the Foundation or to its president-- writer, publisher, and art collector, Lita Hornick.
1991 Addition: Correspondence, manuscripts, publicity files, art work, and printed ephemera received by Lita Hornick and the Kulchur Foundation between 1979 and 1989. Also included are files related to poetry readings sponsored by the Kulchur Foundation during this period as well as correspondence relating to Lita Hornick's graduate work on Dorothy Richardson and Dylan Thomas in the 1940s and 1950s.
2000 Addition: Correspondence, manuscripts, photographs, printed materials, and a video cassette.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in 6 series
Series I: Correspondence, 1961-1993
Series II: Kulchur Press and Kulchur Foundation, 1953-1989
Subseries II.1: Kulchur Magazine, 1961-1966
Subseries II.2 Kulchur Press Editorial Files, 1967-1989
Subseries II.3 Unpublished Manuscripts, 1953-1992
Subseries II.4 Administrative and Financial Records, 1961-1994
Series III: Lita Hornick Files, 1948-1994
Series IV: Photographs, 1950s-1990s
Series V: Artwork, 1965-1980
Series VI: Published Material, 1961-1993
Subjects
Kulchur Foundation.; Berrigan, Ted.; Brainard, Joe, 1942-1994.; Ford, Charles Henri.; Baraka, Imamu Amiri, 1934-; Malanga, Gerard.; Padgett, Ron.; Hornick, Lita R., 1927-; Little magazines.; Beat generation.; Bohemianism.; Literature.; Periodicals--Publishing.; Publishers and publishing.; Financial records.; Lists.; Manuscripts (literary).; Photographs.; Photoprints; Proofs.; Authors.; Critics.; Editors.; Poets.; Publishers.; Women publishers.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located on-site.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Lita Hornick Gift 1987 & 1991.
Lita Hornick Bequest 2000.
06/23/1986 M-86-06-23 Hornick, Lita Gift
1991 M-1991 Papers Hornick, Lita
03/21/2000 M-03-21-00 Papers Hornick, Lita Bequest
Related Material-- at Columbia
Dorothy M. Richardson: the quest for selfhood. Lita Rothbard's Masters Essay
The intricate image; a study of Dylan Thomas. Lita Hornick's Dissertation
- Series I: Correspondence, 1961-1993
  The correspondence series includes letters to and from Lita Hornick and Kulchur Press. Most of the correspondence in editorial or administrative in nature, though as Hornick's lists of friends and business associates overlap considerably, the letters are often social in tone.
  - A, 1965-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Adam, Helen, 1976-1981, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 3 to 4)
  - Allen, Don, 1963, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Antin, David, 1964-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ashbery, John, 1966-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - B, 1964-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 8 to 9)
  - Beck, Julian and Judith, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bergé, Carol, undated and 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Berkson, Bill, 1962-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Berrigan, Ted, 1964-1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Blackburn, Paul, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bockris, Victor, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Boultenhouse, Charles, 1965-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bowering, George, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Brainard, Joe, Undated, 1964-1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - C, 1965-1982, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Cage, John, undated and 1984 (Box 1, Folder 21 to 22)
  - Clark, Tom, 1965-1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Codrescu, Andrei, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cooper, Dennis, undated 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Corman, Cid, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Corso, Gregory, 1968 and 1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Creeley, Robert, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cunningham, Merce, 1972-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 29 to 30)
  - D, 1963-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Dawson, fielding, 1962-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - de Nagy, Tibor, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - di Prima, Diane, undated, 1964-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 5 to 6)
  - Dorn, Ed, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Duncan, Robert, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - E, 1982-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Economou, George, 1962-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Eigner, Larry, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Elmslie, Kenward, 1968-1988 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Eshleman, Caryl, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Eshleman, Clayton 1963-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 14 to 15)
  - F, 1962-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 16 to 17)
  - Fagin, Larry, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ferrari, Mary Selby, 1978-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 20 to 21)
  - Ford, Charles Henri, 1965-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 22 to 23)
  - Fulton, Len, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - G, 1965-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 24 to 25)
  - Ginsberg, 1963-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 26 to 27)
  - Giorno, John, 1969-1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Golde, Morris, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Greenwald, Ted, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Grosvenor, Robert, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gustafson, Jim, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Gysin, Brion, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - H, 1963-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 5 to 6)
  - Hirschman, Jack, 1964-1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Hoffman, Frederick J., 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Hollo, Anselm, 1962-1979 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Howard, Richard, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Ignatow, David, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Irby, Ken, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Jacquette, Yvonne, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Jones, LeRoi, undated and 1961-1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - K, 1964-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 15 to 16)
  - Kaplan, Allan, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Katz, Alex, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Kelly, Robert, 1962-1979 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Kizer, Carolyn, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Koch, Kenneth, undated, 1970-1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Kostelanetz, Richard, 1972-1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Krauss, Ruth, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - L, 1961-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 24 to 25)
  - Lamantia, Philip, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Laughlin, James, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Lavin, Stuart R., 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Lebel, Jean-Jacques, undated and 1982-1987 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - LeSeur, Jerry, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Lenya, Lotte, undated, 1975-1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Levertov, Denise, 1962-1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Levin, Leo and Catherine, 1975-1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Loewinsohn, Ron, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Lowenfels, Walter, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - M, 1964-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 6 to 7)
  - Maas, Willard, 1963-1968 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - MacAdams, Lewis, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Mailer, Norman, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Malanga, Gerard, undated, 1962-1990, (5 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 11 to 15)
  - Manganatti, Donatella, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Mayer, Bernadette, 1975-1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - McClure, Michael, 1962-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 18 to 19)
  - Mekas, Jonas, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Meltzer, David, 1964-1980 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Merrill, James, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Merwin, William Stanley, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Messerli, Douglas, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Monk, Meredith, undated and 1983 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Morris, Robert Lee, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Motherwell, Robert, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - N, 1969-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 28 to 29)
  - Nolan, Pat, 1973-1980 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - North, Charles and Paula, 1970-1982 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - O, undated and 1963-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 32 to 33)
  - O'Hara, Frank, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Olsen, Charles, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Oppenheimer, 1962-1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Orlovsky, Peter, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Owen, Maureen, 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Owens, Rochelle, 1964-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 6 to 7)
  - P, 1963-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 8 to 9)
  - Padgett, Ron, 1964-1990, (3 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 10 to 12)
  - Plymell, Charles, undated and 1975, 1989, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 13 to 14)
  - R, 1963-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 15 to 16)
  - Randall, Margaret, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Rothenberg, Jerome, 1962-1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Ryan, John Fergus, 1964-1978 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - S, 1965-1979 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - S-T, 1980-1989 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Sanders, Ed, 1963, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Saroyan, Aram, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Schwerner, Armand, 1962-1980 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Sinclair, John, 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Snyder, Gary, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Solomon, Holly, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Sorrentino, Gilbert, 1961-1981 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Stepanchev, Stephen, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Swenson, May, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - T, 1962-1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Tomlinson, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Torregian, Sotère, 1973-1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Tyler, Parker, 1965-1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Udoff, Yale, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - V, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Vega, Janine Pommy, 1975-1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Veitch, Tom, 1970-1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Violi, Paul, 1973-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 9 to 10)
  - W, 1963-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 11 to 12)
  - Wakoski, Diane, undated, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Waldman, Anne, 1971-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 14 to 15)
  - Waldman, Frances, 1971-1980 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Warsh, Lewis, 1969-1981 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Whalen, Philip, 1962-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 18 to 19)
  - Williams, Jonathan, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Woolf, Douglas, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Y, 1963-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 22 to 23)
  - Zavatsky, Bill, 1972-1978 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Zukofsky, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Zukofsky, 1961-1972 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Unidentified, Unsigned and Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1963-1993, (3 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 27 to 29)
- Series II: Kulchur Magazine and Kulchur Press, 1953-1989
  This series comprises the bulk of the collection and includes the editorial, administrative, and financial records of Kulchur.
  - Subseries II.1: Kulchur Magazine, 1961-1966
    This subseries contains files for each issue of the magazine that Lita Hornick had a hand in editing-- from Kulchur 3 through magazine's final issue, Kulchur 20 (though the file for Kulchur 4, which was guest-edited by Gilbert Sorrentino, is mostly photostats). These files generally contain the manuscripts for articles and reviews for each issue (often heavily marked up by Ms. Hornick) and hand-written notes about layout and the order in which the pieces should appear.
    - Kulchur #3 Editorial Files (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Kulchur #4, 1961 (mostly Photostats) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kulchur #6, Summer 1962 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Kulchur #7, Autumn, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Kulchur #8, Winter, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Kulchur #9, Spring, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Kulchur #10, Summer, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Kulchur #11, Autumn, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Kulchur #12, Winter, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Kulchur #13, Spring, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Kulchur #14, Summer, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Kulchur # 15, Autumn, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Kulchur #16, Winter, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Kulchur #17, Spring, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Kulchur #18, Summer, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Kulchur #19, Fall, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Kulchur #20, Winter 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Subseries II.2: Editorial Files, 1967-1989
    This subseries is comprised of files for each of the books published by Kulchur Press and Kulchur Foundation, arranged alphabetically by author. Most files will contain an original manuscript, and corrected and uncorrected proofs, cover art or illustrations, as well as any additional material related to the book's production or promotion such as promotional material and invitations to release parties. This series also includes the manuscripts, proofs, and other editorial files for books written by Lita Hornick and published by Kulchur. For files on books authored by Hornick, but not published by Kulchur, see Series III: Lita Hornick Files.
    Additionally, original artwork for Kulchur Press publications (such as Joe Brainard's artwork for Album and Bean Spasms) will be found with the editorial files for those books, rather than in the artwork Series.
    - Adam, Helen
      - Turn Again to Me and Other Poems, 1982
        - Manuscript (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Proofs, (4 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 2 to 5)
          (includes galley proofs, corrected galleys, and page proofs)
        - Paste-up Copy (Box 10, Folder 6)
        - Publicity Material (Box 54)
    - Adam, Helen and Austé
      - Stone Cold Gothic, 1984
        - Manuscript (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - Proofs, (3 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 2 to 4)
    - Antin, David
      - Talking, 1972
        - Cover Designs (Box 12, Folder 1)
        - Manuscript (Box 12, Folder 2)
        - Mechanicals (Box 12, Folder 3)
        - Promotional Material (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Berrigan, Ted and Ron Padgett
      - Bean Spasms, 1967
        - Cover Design and Cover Art, (3 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 1 to 3)
          (Joe Brainard's original Artwork)
        - Original Artwork-- Joe Brainard (Box 13, Folder 4)
        - Photographs (Box 13, Folder 5)
        - Reviews (Box 54)
    - Brainard, Joe
      - Selected Writings, 1971
        - Manuscript (Box 13, Folder 6)
        - Proofs-- Cover (Box 13, Folder 7)
        - Promotional Material (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Ceravolo, Joe
      - Millennium Dust, 1982
        - Manuscript (Box 13, Folder 9)
        - Cover Art (Box 13, Folder 10)
        - Proofs, (4 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 1 to 4)
        - Publicity Material (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Tom Clark
      - At Malibu, 1975
        - Manuscript (Box 14, Folder 6)
        - Proofs, (3 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 7 to 9)
        - Promotional Material (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Elmslie, Kenward
      - Album, 1969
        - Manuscript (Box 15, Folder 1)
        - Original Artwork by Joe Brainard, (3 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 2 to 4)
          (includes "Bev," "The Black Capsule," and "April," as well as other illustrations)
        - Dummies (Box 15, Folder 5)
        - Photostat Proofs (Box 15, Folder 6)
        - Galley Proofs- with Corrections, (3 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - Sung Sex, 1989
        - Proofs, (4 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 7 to 10)
    - Fagin, Larry
      - Rhymes of a Jerk, 1974
        - Manuscript (Box 16, Folder 1)
        - Publicity Material (Box 16, Folder 2)
        - Page Proofs, (3 Folders) (Box 54, Folder 2 to 4)
        - Cover Designs, (2 Folders) (Box 54, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Ferrari, Mary
      - Isle of the Little God, 1981
        - Manuscript (Box 16, Folder 3)
        - Cover Art (Box 16, Folder 4)
        - Proofs, (5 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 5 to 9)
        - Paste-up Pages (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - Promotional Material, (2 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Giorno, John
      - Balling Buddha, 1970
        - Manuscript (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Giorno, John and Richard Bosman
      - Grasping at Emptiness, 1985
        - Art Work (Box 17, Folder 5)
        - Proofs, (2 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 6 to 7)
        - Proofs, (3 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Greenwald, Ted
      - The Licorice Chronicles, 1979
        - Cover Design (Box 55)
        - Page Proofs (3 sets) (Box 55)
    - Hartman, Yuki
      - Ping, 1984
        - Manuscript (Box 17, Folder 4)
        - Proofs, (5 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 5 to 9)
        - Paste-up Pages (Box 17, Folder 10)
        - Publicity Materials (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Hornick, Lita
      - Night Flight, 1978-1982
        - Artwork (Box 19, Folder 1)
        - Manuscript
          - General, (3 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 2 to 4)
          - Introduction (Box 19, Folder 5)
          - Ted Berrigan/Romantic Formalist (Box 19, Folder 6)
          - John Wieners/Tragic Lyricist (Box 19, Folder 7)
          - The Jack Kerouac School of Disembodies Poetics, (2 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 8 to 9)
          - David Antin/Debunker of the "Real" (Box 20, Folder 1)
          - Joe Brainard/Ingenious Ironist, (2 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 2 to 3)
          - The Haunted Land of Helen Adams (Box 20, Folder 4)
          - The Poems of Jack Kerouac, (4 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 5 to 8)
          - Notes on the Records of Giorno Poetry Systems, (3 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 9 to 11)
          - Twelve Paintings in My Collection, (4 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 1 to 4)
        - Proofs, (5 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 5 to 9)
        - Proofs-- David Antin Chapter, (2 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Promotional Materials (Box 22, Folder 3)
        - Reviews (Box 22, Folder 4)
        - Cover Design and Artwork-- Oversize, (2 Folders) (Box 58)
      - Nine Martinis, 1986
        - Artwork, (3 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 5 to 7)
        - Manuscript
          - General (Box 23, Folder 1)
          - Paul Blackburn/Sensual Singer (Box 23, Folder 2)
          - Susan Hall/Out of the Shadows (Box 23, Folder 3)
          - Andrei Codrescu/Sabateur (sic) of History (Box 23, Folder 4)
          - Richard Bosman/Terror as Myth (Box 23, Folder 5)
          - Alice Notley/A Feminine Identity (Box 23, Folder 6)
          - Austé/Romantic Occultist (Box 23, Folder 7)
          - Joseph Ceravolo/Night Bird (Box 23, Folder 8)
          - Miriam Schapiro/Woman Articulate (Box 23, Folder 9)
        - Proofs, (3 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 10 to 12)
        - Promotional Materials, (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 13 to 14)
    - Howe, Susan
      - Defenestration of Prague, 1983
        - Cover Art (Box 24, Folder 1)
        - Manuscript, (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 2 to 3)
        - Proofs, (4 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 4 to 7)
        - Proofs, (2 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Promotional Materials (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Jones, Hettie
      - Poetry Now, 1966
        - Manuscript (Box 25, Folder 4)
        - Permissions (Box 25, Folder 5)
        - Reviews and Contributor List (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Katz, Alex and Kenneth Koch
      - Interlocking Lives, 1970
        - Manuscript (Box 54)
        - Cover Design (Box 25, Folder 7)
        - Proofs, (3 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 8 to 20)
          (includes page proofs, galleys, and bluelines)
        - Proofs (Box 26, Folder 1)
        - Dummy (Box 26, Folder 2)